# **Anamoul** Rouf

I'm a **Product Designer** with **7+ years** of working experience in building bridge between business, technology and human.

I believe in design practice that is data-informed and driven by empathy. I find the balance between complex business requirements and user needs, through a user-centric design approach.

## Work History

# Product Design Manager Truck Lagbe Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh; From MAY 2021 to Continue.

Truck Lagbe is the largest and pioneer in truck & pickup rental service provider.

- I'm leading the most talented a team of 5+ designers and design **functional and useable products** for the current **2M+ & future billion** users.
- Conceive, plan and drive the development of high-end, useful digital products.
- Facilitated the design team in developing and maintaining the design system, implementing the design process to increase team productivity by around 25%.

# Sr. Product Designer ShareTrip Inc.

Dhaka, Bangladesh; From SEP 2018 to APR 2021.

ShareTrip is the country's first and pioneer online travel aggregator (OTA).

- My goal was to craft a functional and delightful experience through web and mobile apps currently consisting of 1.2M+ & future billion users.
- Assembled informative insights from research and interviews. Made strategic
  decisions using rapidly testing and design thinking approach, improved usability
  by about 54%.
- Collaborated & co-ordinated with CEO, engineers, and other stakeholders to define UX problems and improve user engagement and generated about 56% growth in active users in 4 months.
- **Designed and evaluated** a centralized **Design System**. Maintained consistency and continuity, **save around 25%** of designers' and developers' **productive time**.
- Created seamless and intuitive booking experience through the platform with about 86% success rate.

# UX Consultant JoBike

Dhaka, Bangladesh; From JAN 2019 to From JUN 2019.

Jobike is an on-demand bicycle-sharing service. Worked on 3+ web & mobile apps.

- Redesign & automate the support system and also enhance the bicycle battery efficiency by 30%.
- Designed a more **improved & secured** user account **recharge process**, which helps to get positive user reviews.

# UI & UX Designer Beatnik Digital

Dhaka, Bangladesh; From FEB 2016 to FEB 2018.

Beatnik is a 360 creative agency based in Dhaka, Bangladesh.

- Successfully worked on around 25+ web and mobile app design projects for many renowned brands like- Banglalink, Berger Paints BD, Burger King BD, Bengal Meet, IPDC Finance, etc.
- Convinced the importance of User Experience and engaged the core team and stakeholders throughout the design process. Led kick-off meetings, interviews, design studios, and user testings.

https://anamoulrouf.com

anamoulrouf.bd@gmail.com

+880 175 969 3045

in linkedin.com/in/roufuxdesigner

## Education

# **Human-Centered Design**

UCSan Diego (Coursera)

2019 - 20

## **Design Thinking for Innovation**

Darden School of Business (Coursera)

2020 - 21

#### Conducting Usability Testing

The Interaction Design Foundation

2020 - 21

#### Gamification

University of Pennsylvania (Coursera)

2020 - 21

## Foundations of UX Design

Google Career Certificates (Coursera)

2020 - 21

#### **BBS**, Business Studies

National University, Bangladesh.

2005 - 09

+ More

# **UX Research**

- Interview & Survey
- Contextual Inquiry
- Competitive Analysis
- · Heuristic Evaluation
- Think Alouds
- Usability Testing + More

# Design

- Persona & Scenario
- Storyboarding
- Sketches
- Wireframing & Rapid Prototyping
- · High-Fidelity Visual Design
- Design System Design & Development + More

#### Tools

- Figma
- Adobe Xd
- Miro
- FigJam
- Balsamiq
- Zeplin
- Adobe Creative Suit + More

## Work Interest

- AR & VR Design Design for Al-Driven Tech
- User Survey Data Analysis.